<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drull</title>
    <link>https://drull1000.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Drull</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 12:30:10 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drull1000.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How and Why I Started Caring About Privacy</title>
      <link>https://drull1000.github.io/posts/how-and-why-i-started-caring-about-privacy/how-and-why-i-started-caring-about-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 12:30:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drull1000.github.io/posts/how-and-why-i-started-caring-about-privacy/how-and-why-i-started-caring-about-privacy/</guid>
      <description>How and why I started caring about privacy. Just another kid with internet access&amp;hellip; For the most part of my life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t cared a lot about my online privacy, specially when I used to be a kid. I can still remember creating several online accounts and proudly filling all of them with my real private information. I didn&amp;rsquo;t care about what I was putting there, and I had no idea of what they were doing with all that.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-and-why-i-started-caring-about-privacy&#34;&gt;How and why I started caring about privacy.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-another-kid-with-internet-access&#34;&gt;Just another kid with internet access&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part of my life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t cared a lot about my online privacy, specially when I used to be a kid. I can still remember creating several online accounts and proudly filling all of them with my real private information. I didn&amp;rsquo;t care about what I was putting there, and I had no idea of what they were doing with all that. A kid like me would never imagine that those cool apps downloaded on my phone were in reality collecting all of my data and selling it to third parties to generate a profile of me and track my activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But things change… and with change, new opportunities come into our way. So I naturally became more tech-savvy with time and learned more about the world that we live in. I started getting into politics when I was a teenager. I… think that&amp;rsquo;s normal for a teenager who has access to Twitter… I guess… but I have never felt like expressing my own ideas online, since I have always been very discrete and don&amp;rsquo;t like drawing too much attention to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I started learning more about programming and other tech stuff, I came across a YouTube channel from a guy who used to work in Silicon Valley. Now, some of his videos are political and talk about some “weird” things he has seen during all these years working there. My intention here is not to get political, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about my political opinions or what you should believe. My intention is to focus on the privacy side of things and why it matters to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, one thing that called my attention from this channel is that he used to work as a data scientist in San Francisco. During most of his videos, he would talk about why social media is dangerous and why we should stop using it. At first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe what he was saying and though it was just some boomer ranting online, but time proved he was right. In {$current_year}, I believe it is safe to say that most people who use the internet on a daily basis, would be able to come out with at least one negative thing about social media, and it&amp;rsquo;s impact on humans, specially teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe most people who are reading this already know the problems associated with high phone usage, and that most modern apps are designed to be extremely addictive. That makes sense, since the more addicted you are to an app, the more data it is going to be able to collect on you, generating revenue for the company behind it. At this point, this is already basic knowledge for anyone who works in the field or has been using the internet for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What some people seem to fail to understand is that this data collection isn&amp;rsquo;t only about generating an annoying ad before your next YouTube video, but about control. This harvested data can be bought and used by anyone to do almost anything they want with it, and after I realized the risks it can bring to my life, I started taking it a lot more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I see someone or even myself advocating for online privacy on social media or in real life, a lot of comments received are from &lt;del&gt;stupid&lt;/del&gt; people who have never studied about the topic, but like pretending they know something about it &lt;del&gt;probably because they think the number of Twitter likes they get is equal to their IQ score&lt;/del&gt;, love to say that &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;privacy doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t even care about you&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; or the classical &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Nothing to hide, nothing to fear&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and, in my opinion, the worst of all: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;They already have everyone&amp;rsquo;s data, dude, duh&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; (this one only shows conformism from the person&amp;rsquo;s side. It isn&amp;rsquo;t even a valid argument). These comments show that most people, unfortunately, have no idea of what is being done to their data yet, and I don&amp;rsquo;t blame most of them. Some of these thoughts have already passed thought my mind in the past, and I agree that it can be difficult to see what is behind all of this massive data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with all this is that, by knowing your interests, it becomes way easier &lt;strong&gt;to control you and exploit your weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt;. Companies exploit it trying to sell you products, predicting your behavior (sometimes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/16/how-target-figured-out-a-teen-girl-was-pregnant-before-her-father-did/?sh=f10c63066686&#34;&gt;future&lt;/a&gt;) and use all these datapoints to build a profile of you that will be used and abused by marketing experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it was just about trying to sell products to me, I personally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t care much. At the end of the day, I always have my UBlock Origin extension installed and have no money to spend, but it does not stop here. Remember when I said that anyone can buy your data? Yes. The government can collect and buy it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t need to look back too long ago to see how much and how fast society has changed. People are more and more behaving the same way, consuming the same type of content, supporting the same ideas and hating the same people. Even though there are still different groups that combat each other ideologically (for example: left vs right), people who are part of these bubbles are told what to believe and what to fight for. This extreme polarization is beneficial for the government and for companies. The first will have faithful supporters no matter what. The second will squeeze the highest amount of &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/pVDNBsC.jpeg&#34;&gt;revenue&lt;/a&gt; from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowlege is power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyzing some of the events that have occurred not a long time ago, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me that we are heading towards a good direction. Governments are clearly abusing our data and using it to take authoritarian measures, as seen in China and recently in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.republicworld.com/world-news/europe/canada-trudeau-vows-to-freeze-bank-accounts-of-truckers-protesting-covid-vaccine-mandate-articleshow.html&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is unfortunately a trend that is not going to stop any time soon. Actions like these will start happening more often and its consequences will be more harmful as people continue to integrate internet in every aspect of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrating-my-digital-life&#34;&gt;Migrating my digital life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process of becoming privacy focused is not something that happened over the night to me. It was and still is being a slow process that takes effect little by little. I remember starting to switch to Linux after learning that Microsoft has keyloggers built into their system and that windows is a privacy nightmare. Of course, I didn&amp;rsquo;t completely wipe windows off my machine right away. I started with a dual boot, slowly migrating my files, programs and getting used to the system. This is something that I recommend to everyone: If you want more privacy, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t jump in headfirst. It should be a continuous and slow process&lt;/strong&gt;. You should feel comfortable with the changes you make and always try to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After starting to switch to Linux, I started watching some videos about it, and naturally, I got in touch with the FOSS and privacy movement. I started watching a bunch of content creators, reading articles, listening to podcasts and replacing my apps with open source alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 videos in particular that I remember had a huge impact on me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=Y19RFmOxfVM&#34;&gt;Go Incognito: A Guide to Security, Privacy &amp;amp; Anonymity | Front to Back&lt;/a&gt; by Techlore and &lt;a href=&#34;https://piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=94ENNlF_05k&#34;&gt;Delete google from your life now&lt;/a&gt; by The Hated One. Having access to these channels opened my eyes and made my “conversion” a lot easier. Then I started slowly removing google from my life. I started from changing some intrusive settings in my account until finally becoming prepared to flash a degoogled custom ROM to my phone. I still have a Google account, but it is not active at all. I moved from Gmail to ProtonMail, went from Google Drive to filen.io, from YouTube to NewPipe/Piped from Google Chrome to Librewolf, stopped using their search engine by choosing something private and set up a Bitwarden account to store all of my passwords. I have always tried to me a digital minimalist, so switching some services was not that big of a deal, it was just a matter of getting used to something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time, I stopped using social media, deleted all of my tweets, removed photos that contained my face in it and I don&amp;rsquo;t regret it. I love the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to deal with all those schizos from Twitter anymore and don&amp;rsquo;t waste my time getting mad at them for posting cringe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit of stopping to use social media is that you realize you have so much time to get your stuff done. If you still use it, I recommend installing an open source screen time tracker on your phone and testing it for one week. Depending on how many hours you spend, you might reconsider if it is really beneficial to you or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the internet, I follow the principle of &amp;ldquo;Everything you post of online can and will be used against you&amp;rdquo;. This is something that has been proved to be true, and even if you delete things, someone will find a way of bringing it back to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-considerations&#34;&gt;Final considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wrote here all the steps I take and all the tools I use to secure my privacy, this article would become a book, so I want to write a separate post just for that in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with all being said, do I think that all this is worth it? Yes. Can it be done by anyone? Yes, but it depends on your threat model. There are people who can&amp;rsquo;t stop using social media, because that&amp;rsquo;s what they use to make money. Maybe some people need to use Google services because of college, work or whatever else. Some need whatsapp because everyone uses it, and their friends don&amp;rsquo;t want to switch to something better. No one on the internet will be able to tell you what is best for you, but it is important to know of the risks associated with the usage of these platforms, and how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to start taking your privacy more seriously, my advice is to start small. As I said, it should be something continuous and slow. See what you can do for yourself in your time and in your context. I bet you will see the benefits of it and won&amp;rsquo;t regret your decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full OSINT Guide</title>
      <link>https://drull1000.github.io/posts/full-osint-guide/full-osint-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:13:24 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drull1000.github.io/posts/full-osint-guide/full-osint-guide/</guid>
      <description>How to do OSINT - A brief introduction. This is a collection of everything I have learned about OSINT from various resources over the internet. Be aware that some of the tools presented here may change or stop working with time, which is normal. The most important thing you should get out of this is to learn the methods used and be able to replicate them.
The goal of this guide is to show the path one should follow when doing research on a target.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-do-osint---a-brief-introduction&#34;&gt;How to do OSINT - A brief introduction.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of everything I have learned about OSINT from various resources over the internet. Be aware that some of the tools presented here may change or stop working with time, which is normal. The most important thing you should get out of this is &lt;strong&gt;to learn the methods used and be able to replicate them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this guide is to show the path one should follow when doing research on a target. The guide is divided in different sections covering a wide range of topics. Each one of them has their own tools that I recommend and use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page will be updated with time as I find new resources and new tools. Happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-osint&#34;&gt;What is OSINT?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open-source intelligence is the collection and analysis of data gathered from open sources (overt and publicly available sources) to produce actionable intelligence. OSINT is primarily used in national security, law enforcement, and business intelligence functions and is of value to analysts who use non-sensitive intelligence in answering classified unclassified, or proprietary intelligence requirements across the previous intelligence disciplines. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_intelligence&#34;&gt;Read more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSINT is the first phase of hacking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-your-data-safe&#34;&gt;Keeping your data safe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting, it is important to make sure that your data is secure and that you won&amp;rsquo;t reveal your true identity. Ideally, we are not going to interact directly with our target, but it is always essential to stay secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;password-managers&#34;&gt;Password managers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to keep the information you are collecting &lt;strong&gt;as private as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; In order to do that, it is essential to use a password manager like &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com&#34;&gt;Bitwarden.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a strong password and use it for only one account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable 2FA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t save passwords in browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never answer online security questions truthfully, since those are vulnerable to social engineering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid using SMS for 2FA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider unique usernames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;secure-email&#34;&gt;️Secure email&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant step is to use a secure email provider that offers encryption, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com&#34;&gt;Protonmail.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your email address private&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable automatic loading of remote content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t share sensitive data via email. You can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://onionshare.org&#34;&gt;onionshare&lt;/a&gt; to share sensitive files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use aliasing/anonymous forwarding (ex: &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io/?slref=bridsqrgvrnavso&#34;&gt;SimpleLogin&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;encryption&#34;&gt;Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before backing up your data in the cloud, it is encouraged to encrypt it. For that, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptomator.org&#34;&gt;Cryptomator.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sock-puppets&#34;&gt;Sock Puppets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sock puppet is a fake identity you assume on the internet so that you don&amp;rsquo;t give out your real data. &lt;strong&gt;This should never link back to your true identity.&lt;/strong&gt; Sock puppets should look real and be active online to look more legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must generate a fake profile and add fake data to it.&lt;/strong&gt; This data should be the same across all the sock puppets&amp;rsquo; accounts. Remember: women are better at social engineering. Don&amp;rsquo;t use other people&amp;rsquo;s photos, because that could be easily reverse searched. You can use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://thispersondoesnotexist.com&#34;&gt;this person does not exist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sock puppets are of extreme importance in case you are investigating dangerous people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is affordable to you, you should use burner phones and computers to manage the accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a VPN instead of your real IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;searches&#34;&gt;Searches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to talk about search engines and how to better utilize them. When we are searching for something on Google, for example, it is very common to find a bunch of irrelevant and messy results. When we are doing an OSINT investigation, it is important to filter the good results from the bad ones. That&amp;rsquo;s why we use something called search operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;search-operators&#34;&gt;Search operators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of commands you can use to refine your search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results about cats or dogs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results for exact term &amp;ldquo;cats and dogs&amp;rdquo;. If no results are found, related results will be shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;cats and dogs&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fewer dogs in results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats -dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find subdomains of dogs.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;site:dogs.com -www&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More dogs in results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats +dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDFs about cats. Supported file types: pdf, doc(x), xls(x), ppt(x), html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats filetype:pdf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages about dogs from example.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dogs site:example.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages about cats, excluding example.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats -site:example.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page title includes the word &amp;ldquo;dogs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;intitle:dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page text includes the word &amp;ldquo;dogs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;intext:dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page url includes the word &amp;ldquo;cats&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;inurl:cats&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages that include the cached pages for dogs.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cache: dogs.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages include the word &amp;ldquo;cats&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;dogs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats AND dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages include the word &amp;ldquo;cats&amp;rdquo; OR &amp;ldquo;dogs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats OR dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages that include the phrase &amp;ldquo;cats [something] dogs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cats * dogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/alerts&#34;&gt;Google alerts&lt;/a&gt; can alert you of new search results for what you are looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.exploit-db.com/google-hacking-database&#34;&gt;Google Hacking Database&lt;/a&gt; can provide you a list of interesting combinations using search operators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dorksearch.com/&#34;&gt;Dorksearch&lt;/a&gt; for faster google dorking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-people&#34;&gt;For people&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a specific person, a good way to start is to look for the person&amp;rsquo;s name on a search engine. If you want something more specific, you can go over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://whitepages.com&#34;&gt;whitepages&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://truepeoplesearch.com&#34;&gt;truepeoplesearch&lt;/a&gt;, although these websites are more focused on the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pull out voting records of people, you can use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://voterrecords.com&#34;&gt;Voterrecords&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.politicalmoneyline.com/&#34;&gt;politicalmoneyline&lt;/a&gt; to try finding donations to public parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for relatives and friends of the target, since these people might post additional information online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scamdigger.com/&#34;&gt;scamdigger&lt;/a&gt; helps you find if a person your are looking for is in reality a scammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try finding aliases and alternative names of the target and so research on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check death records to see if a person is impersonating someone else who has already died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.statefarm.com/lite-auth/view-insurance-card&#34;&gt;statefarm&lt;/a&gt; If you have the target&amp;rsquo;s phone number and date of birth to see if they have vehicles under state farm and insurance. It also shows a partially redacted email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fastpeopesearch.com&#34;&gt;fastpeoplesearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fastbackgroundcheck.com&#34;&gt;fastbackgroundcheck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://webmii.com&#34;&gt;webmii&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thatsthem.com&#34;&gt;thatsthem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xlek.com&#34;&gt;xlek&lt;/a&gt; aka cubib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blackbookonline.info/&#34;&gt;blackbookonline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pipl.com/&#34;&gt;pipl&lt;/a&gt; - paid/personal information required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://findagrave.com/&#34;&gt;findagrave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ancestry.com/search/collections/60525/&#34;&gt;ancestry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family trees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.familysearch.org/tree/overview&#34;&gt;FamilySearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.familytree.com/&#34;&gt;FamilyTree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geni.com/&#34;&gt;Geni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-criminal-records&#34;&gt;For criminal records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncsc-search.squiz.cloud/s/search.html?collection=ncsc-meta&amp;amp;profile=_default&amp;amp;query=public%20records&#34;&gt;ncsc&lt;/a&gt; has a ton of court records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsopw.gov/&#34;&gt;nsopv&lt;/a&gt; to find sex offender records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bop.gov/inmateloc/&#34;&gt;Federal Bureau of Prisons&lt;/a&gt; Locate the whereabouts of a federal inmate incarcerated from 1982 to the present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hotgunz.com/&#34;&gt;hotgunz&lt;/a&gt; find if a firearm is stolen or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-businesses&#34;&gt;For businesses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are doing OSINT on a business, the first place to look at is their website and social media, specially LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check for company directory in the URL, news, forums, phone numbers, employees, and their positions, photos and what is contained in them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look for photos you might be able to get some data from your target, such as sticky notes, operating systems and metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for the company name in a government website that can give you some legal data, such as directors, CEOs and other names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for complaints and reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencorporates.com&#34;&gt;OpenCorporates&lt;/a&gt; has information on companies and officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indeed.com&#34;&gt;indeed&lt;/a&gt; is useful to see what skills employees need to work in a specific company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencorporates.com/&#34;&gt;opencorporates&lt;/a&gt; for global searches and find officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-websites&#34;&gt;For websites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some data you can extract from websites are: technologies used, IP addresses, who is hosting it, subdomains, etc…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centralops.net/co/&#34;&gt;CentralOps&lt;/a&gt; can be used to find &lt;strong&gt;a lot of information&lt;/strong&gt; about the host. It is possible to find sensitive information on who is hosting the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dnslytics.com/reverse-ip&#34;&gt;dnslytics&lt;/a&gt; Reverse IP search. If someone hosts their own server, you can use it to find other registered websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check for website changes, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://changetower.com&#34;&gt;changetower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ahrefs.com/backlink-checker&#34;&gt;ahrefs&lt;/a&gt; is a website that allows you to look for backlinks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shodan can also be used to look for vulnerabilities, if you have an IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some websites might have some subdomains online that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be available to the public. You can use search operators to look for some subdomains like “dev”, “forums”, “admin”, &amp;ldquo;adm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;VPN&amp;rdquo; by subtracting www and adding inurl: URL. You can use sublist3r, OWASP Amass and &lt;a href=&#34;https://crt.sh&#34;&gt;crt.sh&lt;/a&gt; to list subdomains of a website&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org&#34;&gt;Wayback machine&lt;/a&gt; can show you old versions of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Google, you can open the cached website by clicking on the arrow next to the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://builtwith.com/&#34;&gt;BuiltWith&lt;/a&gt; to find the technologies used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spiderfoot.net/&#34;&gt;spiderfoot&lt;/a&gt; is a software that allows you to scan a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.httrack.com/&#34;&gt;HTtrack&lt;/a&gt; clones a website. Useful to keep an offline copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://whois.domaintools.com&#34;&gt;domaintools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://urlscan.io/&#34;&gt;urlscan.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://viewdns.info/&#34;&gt;viewdns.info&lt;/a&gt; a lot of useful tools to analyze websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subfinder, assetfinder for finding subdomains. CLI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gowitness: CLI tool for taking screenshots of domains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-phone-numbers&#34;&gt;For phone numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For searching phone numbers, you can first look for them on Google and see what comes out. If you don&amp;rsquo;t get interesting results, try searching with hifens, area codes or even spell the numbers. Play with the syntax. Even a phone emoji 📱 can be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If google or any other search engine does not work, the websites used for searching people can also be used for phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the person&amp;rsquo;s email, you can test if they have a phone number associated with the account by going to reset password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://truecaller.com&#34;&gt;Truecaller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phoneinfoga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-birthdates&#34;&gt;For birthdates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to look for someone&amp;rsquo;s birthday, try looking for that on Google and use search operators. Twitter is a great place to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-resumes&#34;&gt;For resumes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google and other search engines can easily help you find resumes. Try looking for images and PDFs. You can also look for the person&amp;rsquo;s name on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can combine search operators to look for them in places like google, Dropbox, scribd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indeed.com&#34;&gt;indeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobvertise.com&#34;&gt;search resumes free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-iot-and-connected-devices&#34;&gt;For IoT and connected devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find vulnerable IoT devices on &lt;a href=&#34;https://shodan.io&#34;&gt;shodan.io&lt;/a&gt; and find IP addresses, location, open vulnerable ports (such as 3389) and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wigle.net&#34;&gt;wigle.net&lt;/a&gt; is a map of wireless networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-aircraft&#34;&gt;For aircraft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most aircraft can be tracked down due to the unencrypted data transmitted. Every aircraft has a unique serial number and there are websites capable of tracking them, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://radarbox.com&#34;&gt;radarbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can copy the plane number and look for more info about it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://aviationdb.net&#34;&gt;aviationdb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also listen to the conversation between the pilots and the control tower on &lt;a href=&#34;https://liveatc.net&#34;&gt;liveatc.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flightradar24.com&#34;&gt;flightradar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-license-plates&#34;&gt;For license plates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://findbyplate.com/&#34;&gt;findbyplate&lt;/a&gt; can find information of a vehicle if you have its license plate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media can be a goldmine for OSINT researchers. It is incredible the amount of data someone can get from a specific person just by looking at their profile. When analyzing someone&amp;rsquo;s profile, try to look for everything you can. Photos, relatives, workplace, check-ins, friends, interests, etc…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweets from a person can be very revealing, and usually people put everything about their lives online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Twitter OSINT, there are tools that can help you with your investigation, but you should start playing with the search bar. Twitter has search operators that can be used to narrow down the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the standard search operators, Twitter has some specific ones, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent from the NASA account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;from:nasa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replying to NASA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;to:nasa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentioning NASA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@nasa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even look for geocodes with a km range. All you need is the latitude and longitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full list can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-api/v1/rules-and-filtering/search-operators&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://socialbearing.com&#34;&gt;socialbearing&lt;/a&gt; can search based on geolocation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitonomy.com&#34;&gt;twitonomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tweetbeaver.com&#34;&gt;tweetbeaver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spoonbill.io&#34;&gt;spoonbill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tinfoleak.com&#34;&gt;tinfoleak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://botometer.osome.iu.edu/&#34;&gt;botometer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twint CLI tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;facebook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Facebook, you can use the search bar and narrow down some results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some search operators are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show photos of lizards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;photos of Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook also has OCR features. That means you can find images by searching for the text contained in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find an account&amp;rsquo;s ID by looking at the source code of it, or by going to &lt;a href=&#34;https://findmyfbid.me/&#34;&gt;findmyfbid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intelx.io/tools?tab=facebook&#34;&gt;intelx.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;instagram&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the Instagram OSINT is covered in the photos section, but there are some tools that can be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at whom the person follows in their account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.codeofaninja.com/find-instagram-user-id&#34;&gt;codeofaninja intagram id&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When investigating YouTube videos, it is useful to do some reverse image search on the content we are watching. In order to do that, we can use some tools like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenevidence.amnestyusa.org/&#34;&gt;citizen evidence amnesty usa&lt;/a&gt; website to pull extra data from the video and get thumbnails to search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reddit&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit is a popular place on the internet where a lot of people post a wide range of different topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.resavr.com/&#34;&gt;resavr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unddit.com/&#34;&gt;unddit&lt;/a&gt;are tools that allow us to find deleted comments and posts from reddit threads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;snapchat&#34;&gt;Snapchat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snapchat has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://map.snapchat.com&#34;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;. You can look for snaps in a certain area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;linkedin&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn is an awesome place to look for connections and work information of someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to find a person&amp;rsquo;s full name, you can install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mxrch/revealin&#34;&gt;Revealin&lt;/a&gt; and use it on the terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything you have from your target is a picture, &lt;strong&gt;extract everything you can from it.&lt;/strong&gt; Is it a car picture? Does it have a plate? What&amp;rsquo;s the side of the steering wheel? What are the surroundings?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reverse-image-search&#34;&gt;Reverse image search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can look for the image source by using a search engine that has a reverse image search feature, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://images.google.com&#34;&gt;Google image search&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://Yandex.com&#34;&gt;Yandex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yandex has the ability to search for similar pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can combine it with search operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your results are not good, you can try using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.remove.bg/&#34;&gt;remove.bg&lt;/a&gt; to remove its background and isolate a person in the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tineye.com&#34;&gt;TinEye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exif-data&#34;&gt;EXIF data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EXIF data is metadata that can be viewed from an image. It can reveal location, device used to take the picture, time and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laramies/metagoofil&#34;&gt;metagoofil&lt;/a&gt; to harvest data from different files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pic2map.com/&#34;&gt;pic2map&lt;/a&gt; Shows where the image was taken based on the metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;satellite-images&#34;&gt;Satellite images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to do some physical location OSINT, you should check satellite photos of the location and absorb all you can about the place. Entrances, parking lots, employees and their dress code, badge readers, security, cameras… everything is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deepfakes&#34;&gt;Deepfakes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deepfakes are gaining popularity quick, and they can be used in a bunch of different ways. As they get more real, spotting them becomes harder, so there are tools out there to help us detect deep fakes, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://deepware.ai/&#34;&gt;deepware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credentials-discovery&#34;&gt;Credentials discovery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usernames&#34;&gt;Usernames&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://whatsmyname.app/&#34;&gt;whatsmyname&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://namechk.com&#34;&gt;Namechk&lt;/a&gt; are good tools to see where a username is being used, and its accounts tied to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an awesome way to find old accounts that may contain critical information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherlock is a python CLI tool that looks for usernames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://knowem.com/&#34;&gt;knowem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;emails&#34;&gt;Emails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com&#34;&gt;Have I been pwned&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to look for emails that have been found in data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good technique is to simply go to the Gmail login and see if the email exists. You can even click on “I forgot my password” and see if there are other emails linked to that account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to search for emails related to companies and its employees, you can check its name on &lt;a href=&#34;https://hunter.io&#34;&gt;hunter.io&lt;/a&gt;. This website can give you emails and show you their domain patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to verify if the emails are valid, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://email-checker.net/validate&#34;&gt;email-checker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scylla.so&#34;&gt;Scylla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://phonebook.cz&#34;&gt;phonebook.cz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;passwords&#34;&gt;Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are talking about passwords in OSINT, we are talking about finding breached credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By finding email and passwords, we can analyze them and look for a potential pattern that might come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://dehashed.com&#34;&gt;dehashed.com&lt;/a&gt; to see if a login has been breached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are dealing with a hashed password, a good thing to do is to try dehashing it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://hashes.com&#34;&gt;hashes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-state&#34;&gt;Real state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When investigating real state, there are some tools that can help us get access to public records, information on who is selling it, etc…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some websites are: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redfin.com/&#34;&gt;redfin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zillow.com/&#34;&gt;zillow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biggerpockets.com/&#34;&gt;biggerpockets&lt;/a&gt;. Note that not every house is going to be available on those websites for you to check, but it can be useful in a few cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-web&#34;&gt;Deep web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take caution when accessing websites in the deep web.&lt;/strong&gt; Never reveal your true identity or use the same email to create accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deep web has a lot of websites that can help you find data breaches and other information that is not indexed in the surface web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://metrics.torproject.org/exonerator.html&#34;&gt;exonarator&lt;/a&gt; allows you to enter an IP address and date to find out whether that address was used as a Tor relay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ahmia.fi/&#34;&gt;ahmia&lt;/a&gt; searches hidden services on the deep web. It can be used in the surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thehidden.wiki/&#34;&gt;TheHiddenWiki&lt;/a&gt; has a list of hidden services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ddosecrets.com/wiki/Distributed_denial_of_secrets&#34;&gt;ddosecrets&lt;/a&gt; similar to wikileaks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frameworks&#34;&gt;Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSINT frameworks are basically a collection of tools in one place. Some of them are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osintframework.com&#34;&gt;OSINT framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recon-ng&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maltego&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunchly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;report-writing&#34;&gt;Report writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should write an easy-to-read report containing the information that you found about the target and the steps necessary to get to them. Good reports use a non-technical language should be accessible to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can add a timeline report logging your steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a profile of your target with quick information found and some links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this website.</title>
      <link>https://drull1000.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drull1000.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello This blog is a place for me to share my programming and hacking knowlege with the world. This is where I post some things I have been writing to myself, but want to share with the world. Maybe not everything here will be tech related, but that&amp;rsquo;s my focus.
But who am I? I am a computer science student who likes coding and hacking. I consider myself to be a privacy advocate, therefore, I like the FOSS movement, linux, simplicity and security.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is a place for me to share my programming and hacking knowlege with the world. This is where I post some things I have been writing to myself, but want to share with the world. Maybe not everything here will be tech related, but that&amp;rsquo;s my focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-who-am-i&#34;&gt;But who am I?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a computer science student who likes coding and hacking. I consider myself to be a privacy advocate, therefore, I like the FOSS movement, linux, simplicity and security.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
